<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<rdf:RDF
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:food="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#">
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Yeung_Chow_fried_rice">
    <food:abstract>Yeung Chow fried rice (Chinese: ????; pinyin: Yang Zhou Chao Fan; variously Romanised Yangchow Yung Chow, Yang Chow, Yangzhou, Yeong Chow) is a popular Chinese-style wok fried rice dish in many Chinese restaurants in China, the Americas, Australia, United Kingdom, Vietnam, Indonesia and the Philippines. The ingredients vary, but there are staple items like: Cooked rice (preferably day old because freshly cooked rice is too sticky) Cooked shrimp Diced cha shao/char siu pork or Lap Cheong Scallions (spring onions or green onions), chopped, including green end fresh vegetables such as Kai-lan, carrots, peas, corn, bamboo shoots, etc. Eggs Some variations of the dish include other vegetables such as peas, carrots and corn. The peas may be a replacement for the green onions.  Some western Chinese restaurants also use soy sauce to flavor the rice.A variant with small pieces of chicken also added is often sold in the UK as special fried rice.YangZhou fried rice is a perhaps the most well-known dish of the city of YangZhou, JiangSu province. The recipe was invented by Qing China's Yi Bingshou (1754–1815) and the dish was named Yang Zhou fried rice since Yi was once the regional magistrate of Yangzhou. It is often served with thousand fish soup. There are two ways of cooking the dish in terms of the preparation of the egg scrambled. The first variation is known as \"silver covered gold\", in which the egg is scrambled separately before mixing with the rice. The alternative \"gold covered silver\" method is described as pouring the liquid egg over the rice and vegetables mix and frying the two together. Legend has it that the best cooks of YangZhou fried rice will create the dish with a rice grain to egg piece ratio of 5:1 or even 3:1.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Yeung_Chow_fried_rice</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Shaobing">
    <food:abstract>For other uses see Shao bing (disambiguation)Shaobing (sh?o b?ng), also written shao bing or sao bing, is a type of baked, unleavened, layered flatbread bread in Chinese cuisine. Shaobing can be made with or without stuffing, and with or without sesame on top. Shaobing contains a variety of stuffings that can be grouped into two main flavors: savory or sweet. Some common stuffings include red bean paste, black sesame paste, stir-fried mung beans with egg and tofu, braised beef, smoked meat, or beef or pork with spices.Shaobing is not very well known in southern China, unlike other northern dishes like mantou, baozi, and youtiao. Some unique varieties of shaobing can be completely unheard of in the south. Different types of shaobing are often associated with certain cities and towns.Shaobing is a common breakfast item. Filled shaobing are usually eaten with soy milk and tea, while unfilled ones are usually eaten with steamed eggs or a breakfast meat dish. In the Mandarin cuisine tradition, shaobing are served with hot pot (hu?gu?) in winter or soy milk.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Shaobing</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Corn_crab_soup">
    <food:abstract>Corn crab soup is a dish found in Chinese cuisine, American Chinese cuisine, and Canadian Chinese cuisine. The soup is actually cream of corn soup with egg white and crab meat or imitation crab meat added. It is most likely of southern Chinese origin.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Corn_crab_soup</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Edible_bird&apos;s_nest">
    <food:abstract>Edible bird's nests are bird nests that are prepared and eaten by humans, particularly prized in Chinese culture due to their rarity and supposedly exquisite flavor. They are among the most expensive animal products consumed by humans, with an average nest selling for $2,500 (US) per kilogramme for end-consumers in Asia. The nests have been used in Chinese cooking for over 400 years, most often as bird's nest soup.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Edible_bird's_nest</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Duck_blood_and_vermicelli_soup">
    <food:abstract>Duck blood and vermicelli soup (Chinese: ?????) is a traditional delicacy of Nanjing, capital of Jiangsu province, and is also eaten in other regions of China. A similar dish is also eaten in Poland, Belarus and Lithuania where it's called czernina.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Duck_blood_and_vermicelli_soup</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Orange_chicken">
    <food:abstract>Orange chicken (simplified Chinese: ???; traditional Chinese: ???; pinyin: chénpí j?; Wade–Giles: ch'en²-p'i³-chi¹; Jyutping: can4 pei4 gai1) is an American Chinese dish of Hunan origin. The variety of orange chicken most commonly found at North American fast food restaurants consists of chopped, battered, and fried chicken pieces coated in a sweet orange-flavored chili sauce, which thickens or caramelizes to a glaze. While the dish is very popular in the United States, it is most often found as a variation of General Tso's chicken rather than the dish found in mainland China.In most countries in the western hemisphere, the names \"orange chicken\", \"orange peel chicken\", \"orange flavor chicken\", and \"tangerine chicken\" are typically used for this particular dish. In Chinese, however, the dish is always known as \"???\", literally \"old peel chicken\", referring to dried orange or tangerine peel, which is used in traditional Chinese medicine as well as cooking. For restaurants outside of Asia, fresh orange peel is often used instead, or even no peel at all.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Orange_chicken</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Red_tortoise_cake">
    <food:abstract>Red tortoise cake (Chinese: ???; Pe?h-?e-j?: Âng-Ku-Kóe) is a small round or oval shaped Chinese pastry with soft sticky glutinous rice flour skin wrapped around a sweet filling in the centre.It is molded to resemble a tortoise shell and is presented resting on a square piece of banana leaf. As suggested by its name, red tortoise cakes are traditionally red in color and has a sticky chewy texture when eaten.Red tortoise cakes are shaped like tortoise shells because the Chinese traditionally believed that eating tortoises would bring longevity to those who are eating it and bring about good fortune and prosperity.Considered to be auspicious items, these sweet pastries are especially prepared during important festivals such as Chinese New Year as offerings to the Chinese deities.Red tortoise cakes are also prepared for occasions that are culturally important to the Chinese such as a newborn baby's first month or birthdays of the elderly. Eating red tortoise cakes during these times are meant to represent blessings for the child and longevity for the elderly. In modern times, red tortoise cakes continue to be important food items during Chinese festivals in many countries such as Singapore, Malaysia, Indonesia, China and Taiwan and southern Thailand provinces such as Phuket,Phang-Nga and Trang. However, eating red tortoise cakes in these countries is no longer restricted to special occasions for red tortoise cakes are also commercially available in many pastry shops and bakeries.There are two main components in red tortoise cakes, the skin and the filling. The skin is made mostly from glutinous rice flour and sweet potato whereas the fillings are made from precooked ingredients such as mung bean or grounded peanuts and sugar. After kneading and molding the ingredients together, the red tortoise cakes are steamed on a piece of banana leaf. In countries such as Singapore, these pastries are popular snack items and are especially popular with children because of their sweet and savory taste. In fact, many bakeries in Singapore have created red tortoise cakes in a variety of assorted flavors, including jelly and red bean, to cater to all tastes and preferences.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Red_tortoise_cake</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Soy_milk">
    <food:abstract>Soy milk, also referred to as soymilk or soya milk, is a plant milk produced bysoaking dried soybeans and grinding them in water.A traditional staple of Asian cuisine, soy milk is a stable emulsion of oil, water and protein. Soy milk can be produced at home using a soy milk machine.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Soy_milk</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Poon_choi">
    <food:abstract>Poon Choi (pronounced: pun4 coi3), also known as pun choi or Big Bowl Feast,  is a traditional type of dish originating from Hong Kong village Cantonese cuisine. It may also be found in different parts of Hong Kong. It is served in wooden, porcelain or metal basins due to its size and communal style of consumption.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Poon_choi</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
