<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<rdf:RDF
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:food="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#">
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Cassoeula">
    <food:abstract>The Cassoeula (from old cazza), sometimes Italianized Cazzuola or Cazzola (Italian word for trowel) or bottaggio (probably derived from the French word potage) is a typical winter dish popular in Northern Italy, mostly in Lombardy. The dish has a strong, decisive flavour, and was a favourite of conductor Arturo Toscanini. One writer describes it as a \"noble, ancient Milanese dish\", and writes of the inexpressible \"pleasure that it furnishes the soul as well as the palate, especially on a wintry day\".@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cassoeula</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Galvanina">
    <food:abstract>Galvanina is an Italian brand of bottled water and fruit-juice-flavored sodas. The water's source is a spring that is located 1,000 feet above sea level on the hill of Rimini, at the foot of the Apennine Mountains in northeastern Italy.Galvanina bottled waters and sodas are imported to the United States by R &amp; V Imports, LLC in Lake Forest, Illinois. As of late 2010, FreshDirect offered this water via private label. It also is the product sold under the house label of Whole Foods.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Galvanina</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Carciofi_alla_romana">
    <food:abstract>Carciofi alla romana, literally \"roman-style artichokes\", is a typical dish of Roman cuisine. In Rome, it is prepared in each household and served in all restaurants in spring-time. Together with the Carciofi alla giudia, it represents one of the most famous artichoke dishes of the Roman cuisine.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Carciofi_alla_romana</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Rollatini">
    <food:abstract>Rollatini (sometimes also spelled rolatini or rolletini) is an Italian-style dish (called rollatini di melanzane in faux Italian) that is usually made with thin slices of eggplant, which are dusted in wheat flour or lightly breaded and covered with ricotta and often other cheeses and seasonings, then rolled up and baked. Alternatively, veal, chicken, or fish may be used in place of the eggplant.Rollatini is not an actual Italian word; in Italy the dish is known as involtini (e.g., involtini di melanzane).@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Rollatini</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Sanfaustino">
    <food:abstract>Sanfaustino is a brand of effervescent mineral water.Since 1894, Sanfaustino is sourced from a spring in Villa San Faustino, Province of Perugia, Umbria, Italy.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Sanfaustino</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Asiago_cheese">
    <food:abstract>Asiago /??si????o?/ is an Italian cow's milk cheese that can assume different textures, according to its aging, from smooth for the fresh Asiago (Asiago Pressato) to a crumbly texture for the aged cheese (Asiago d'allevo) of which the flavor is reminiscent of Parmesan. The aged cheese is often grated in salads, soups, pastas, and sauces while the fresh Asiago is sliced to prepare panini or sandwiches; it can also be melted on a variety of dishes and cantaloupe.As Asiago has a protected designation of origin (Denominazione di Origine Protetta or DOP, see below), the only \"original\" Asiago is produced in the alpine area of the town of Asiago, province of Vicenza, in the Veneto region. Asiago cheese is one of the most typical products of the Veneto region. It was, and still is, the most popular and widely used cheese in the DOP area where it is produced. The production area is strictly defined: it starts from the meadows of the Po Valley and finishes in the Alpine pastures between the Asiago Plateau and the Trentino's highlands. The officially designated area where the milk is collected and Asiago DOP cheese is produced, extends to four provinces in the north-east of Italy: the entire area of Vicenza and Trento and part of the provinces of Padua and Treviso. Asiago cheese which is produced and matured in dairies located more than 600 m (2,000 ft) above sea level, using milk from farms also more than 600 m (2,000 ft) above sea level, is entitled to the additional label \"Product of the Mountains\". Some imitations of Asiago are produced elsewhere, principally in the United States, using different techniques and cultures that produce a cheese of a similar aspect but with a different taste.  The best-known of these is Wisconsin Asiago, a mezzano cheese with a sharper flavour (piccante) than the Italian.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Asiago_cheese</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Tiramisu">
    <food:abstract>Tiramisu (from Italian, spelled tiramisù, [ti?ami?su], meaning \"pick me up\" or \"lift me up\") is a popular coffee-flavoured Italian dessert. It is made of ladyfingers (Italian: Savoiardi, [savo?jardi]) dipped in coffee, layered with a whipped mixture of eggs, sugar, and mascarpone cheese, flavoured with cocoa.  The recipe has been adapted into many varieties of cakes and other desserts. Its origins are often disputed between Italian regions such as Veneto, Friuli Venezia Giulia, Piedmont, and others.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Tiramisu</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Pecorino_Romano">
    <food:abstract>Pecorino Romano is a hard, salty Italian cheese, often used for grating, made out of sheep's milk (the Italian word pecora, from which the name derives, means sheep). Pecorino Romano was a staple in the diet for the legionaries of ancient Rome. Today, it is still made according to the original recipe and is one of Italy's oldest cheeses but, despite the name, most of its production occurs in Sardinia. On the first of May, Roman families traditionally eat Pecorino with fresh fava beans, during a daily excursion in the Roman Campagna. It is mostly used in Central and Southern Italy.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Pecorino_Romano</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#San_Pellegrino">
    <food:abstract>San Pellegrino (also S. Pellegrino) is an Italian brand of mineral water, and assorted real-fruit beverages made from it, with naturally occurring carbonation and additional carbonation added by the bottler, produced and bottled by Nestlé at San Pellegrino Terme, in the Province of Bergamo, Lombardy, Italy. The water naturally contains carbon dioxide and at least the following chemical elements in amounts of 100 or more micrograms per liter:  calcium, chloride, fluorine, lithium, magnesium, nitrogen, potassium, silicon, sodium, and the non-radioactive form of strontium. Outside of Italy, San Pellegrino is portrayed as a luxury and expensive bottled water, despite the fact that it can be bought for approximately US $2 in many convenience and  grocery stores. Owned by Nestlé since 1997, San Pellegrino is exported to most countries in Europe, the Americas, Australasia and the Middle East, as well as to Japan, Taiwan, and Hong Kong.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/San_Pellegrino</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Food#Macaroni">
    <food:abstract>Macaroni is a variety of dry pasta, originating from Italy, made with durum wheat. Macaroni usually does not contain eggs and is normally cut in short, hollow shapes. It may be straight or curved, in which case it is frequently called elbow macaroni. Elbow maraconi is more common in the US and Canada, while British macaroni tends to be straight. Although home machines exist that can make macaroni shapes, macaroni is usually made commercially by large-scale extrusion. The curved shape is caused by different speeds on each side of the pasta tube as it comes out of the machine. The name comes from the Italian maccheroni, plural form of maccherone. A different name, chifferi or lumaconi, refers to bigger size of elbow-shape pasta.According to a widespread misconception, macaroni was taken to Italy by Marco Polo, returning to Venice from China in 1292. This hypothesis has long been disproved, since it seems that macaroni was already used in Italy at least a century before, like pasta in general; Moroccan geographer Muhammad al-Idrisi, who lived in Sicily, documented macaroni in Sicily and in particular in Trabia.The academic consensus supports that the word is derived from the Greek ??????? (makaria), a kind of barley broth which was served to commemorate the dead, which in turn comes from ??????? (makares), \"blessed dead\", and that from ???????? (makarios), collateral of ????? (makar), meaning \"blessed, happy\". The Italian linguist G. Alessio argues that the word can have two origins: the first from the Medieval Greek ?????????? (makar?neia) \"dirge\" (stated in sec. XIII by James of Bulgaria), which would be passed to mean \"funeral meal\" and then \"food to serve\" during this office (see today's ????????? - machar?nia in Eastern Thrace, in the sense of \"rice-based dish served at the funeral\"), in which case the term would be composed of the double root of ???????? \"blessed\" and ??????? (ai?nios), \"eternally\", and the second from the Greek ??????? \"barley broth\", which would have added the suffix -one.In North America, macaroni is most associated with the \"elbow\" shape commonly found in American-style macaroni and cheese. \"Elbow macaroni\" is also used in a milk pudding, similar to rice pudding, called macaroni pudding.In areas with large Chinese populations open to Western cultural influence, such as Hong Kong, Macao, Malaysia and Singapore, the local Chinese have adopted macaroni as an ingredient for Chinese-style Western cuisine. In Hong Kong's cha chaan teng (\"Tea Restaurant\") and Southeast Asia's kopi tiam (\"coffee shop\"), macaroni is cooked in water and then washed of starch, and served in clear broth with ham or frankfurter sausages, peas, black mushrooms, and optionally eggs, reminiscent of noodle soup dishes. This is often a course for breakfast or light lunch fare.@en</food:abstract>
    <food:name>http://dbpedia.org/resource/Macaroni</food:name>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
